Md Shadman Tajwar Haque

600 Fleet Street, Toronto, ON, M5V 1B7 (647) 510 6867 tajwar@ieee.org tajwar.ml linkedin.com/in/tajwarhaque

Summary

A Masters of Engineering in Electrical and Computer Engineering graduate with technical work experience in the Telecommunications and Health Care Industry. An active member of IEEE since 2016, while volunteering under several organizations across the Asia Pacific region under several roles.

Education

University of Windsor, ON, Canada Masters of Engineering – Electrical and Computer Engineering June, 2020 – August, 2021

American International University – Bangladesh (AIUB), Dhaka, Bangladesh Bachelor of Science – Electrical and Electronics Engineering August, 2014 – February, 2018

Publication

Design and Implementation of an IoT based Automated Agricultural Monitoring and Control System – 2019 International Conference on Robotics, Electrical and Signal Processing Techniques (ICREST) [Published: February 21, 2019]

Link: <u>ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/8644212</u>

Experience

Web Developer, ExtraEd, Toronto, ON, Canada

June, 2021 - Present

Company Website: extraed.ca

- Design the Back-end of the company website using JavaScript, PHP and MySQL
- Work on Search Engine Optimization (SEO)

Programmer, C and T Home Care Limited, New York, NY, USA January, 2020 – June, 2020

Company Website: candthomecare.com

- Develop the company website using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and PHP
- Work on numerous documents and media content using Adobe Suite (Illustrator, Photoshop, After Effects)
- Work on Customer Relation Management using QuickBase

Service Assurance and Experience Technology Intern, Banglalink Digital Communications Limited, Dhaka, Bangladesh

May, 2018 - August, 2018

Company Website: banglalink.net

- Cleaned up raw data and created daily reports using Microsoft Excel and Access.
- Prepared Weekly presentations based on weekly customer data using Microsoft PowerPoint

Key Skills

- Python (NumPy, Matplotlib, Pandas, Seaborn)
- Machine Learning (Scikit Learn, Tensorflow, Keras)
- MATLAB
- Data Visualization (Tableau and Power BI)
- Database (MySQL)
- Excel

Interests

- Machine Learning
- Computer Vision
- Data Science
- Analytics

Projects

Link to Projects: projects.tajwar.ml

Prediction of Carbon Emission of Cars, [/Carbon-Emission]

- Cleaned and Visualized raw dataset of car specifications using Pandas
- Visualized and analyzed various parameters to find trend for carbon emissions
- Created a model using linear regression supervised machine learning technique

Drug Suggestion, [/Drug-Suggestion]

- Cleaned up raw Kaggle dataset using pandas
- Used decision tree supervised machine learning technique to build a model for suggesting optimal drug based on patient information
- Visualized the decision tree using Matplotlib and seaborn

Bank Stock Analysis, [/Capstone-Project-Bank-Stock-Analysis]

- Used Pandas Data Reader to obtain clean up Bank Stock data from Yahoo Finance
- Used Seaborn to visualize and compare statistics from Bank of America, Citigroup, Goldman Sachs, JPMorgan Chase, Morgan Stanley, Wells Fargo
- Visualized Distribution plots, Line plots, Moving Averages, Heatmap and Cluster-map for more comparisons

911 Calls Analysis, [/Capstone-Project-911-Calls]

- Cleaned raw dataset using Pandas
- Used pandas to create pivot tables to transform raw data
- Created various visualizations using matplotlib and seaborn for analysis

Reference will be provided upon request